<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Rodrigo Aguayo</title>
    <link>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Rodrigo Aguayo</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projecting the freshwater future in Western Patagonia</title>
      <link>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/neural_hydrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/neural_hydrology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exploring the integration of LSTMs and glacier evolution&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;screen reader text&#34; title=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glacier uncertainties in the Southern Andes</title>
      <link>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/glacier_uncertanties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/glacier_uncertanties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assessing the glacier projection uncertainties from a catchment perspective using the OGGM model&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;screen reader text&#34; title=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncertainties are a major problem in glacier modelling, especially at regional scales such as Patagonia, where we do not have much data to validate our results. Previous studies have shown that model uncertainties (including boundary conditions such as climate or calibration strategy) are the main source of uncertainty until mid-century. At the same time, however, studies show that &amp;ldquo;the projected evolution is only slightly affected by the choice of climate data products used in the past and the spatial resolution of future climate projections&amp;rdquo;. To disentangle the future of glaciers in Patagonia and the relative importance of the different sources of uncertainty from a catchment perspective, we developed an experiment to analyse the impact of different glacier outlines volume datasets, climate datasets, GCMs, SSPs, and bias correction methods. This a part of my PhD thesis&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PatagoniaMet v1.0 (PMET)</title>
      <link>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/patagoniamet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/patagoniamet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do we really need a dataset for Western Patagonia?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;screen reader text&#34; title=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short answer: &lt;strong&gt;Yes!&lt;/strong&gt; High-quality hydrometeorological observations contributes to high-quality policies and management of natural resources. Conversely, unrepresentative, poorly collected, or erroneously archived data introduce uncertainty regarding the magnitude, rate, and direction of environmental change, undermining confidence in decision-making processes. The use of climate variables in any kind of environmental research requires quality-controlled and serially complete datasets. These datasets are used to assess most of the key aspects of climate change, such as temporal trends in mean values and variability, or extreme events. Therefore, data acquired from measurements do not always represent the real behaviour of the observed processes, and need to be corrected under homogenization schemes. Furthermore, hydrometeorological data needs to be Findable, Accessible, Interoperable and Reusable (FAIR data), requirements that are often not fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address these limitations, we present PatagoniaMet v1.0 (PMET), a compilation of observed hydrometeorological data (PMET-obs), and a daily gridded product of precipitation and maximum and minimum temperature (PMET-sim; 0.05º, 1980-2020). PMET-obs was developed considering a 4-step quality control process applied to 344 hydrometeorological time series (precipitation, air temperature, streamflow and lake levels) obtained from nine institutions in Chile and Argentina. Based on this dataset and atmospheric reanalysis data (ERA5), PMET-sim was developed using statistical bias correction processes (e.g., quantile mapping), spatial regression models (random forest) and hydrological methods (Budyko framework).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dataset is part of my PhD thesis. Publication is coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land cover change and forest hydrology</title>
      <link>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/forest_hydrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/forest_hydrology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assessing the impacts of land cover change on the water cycle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;screen reader text&#34; title=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydrological signature and coastal interface</title>
      <link>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/northern_patagonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/northern_patagonia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hydrological signature influence on Chilean aquaculture under climate change and landscape scenarios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;screen reader text&#34; title=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIO = Rivers Influencing the Ocean</title>
      <link>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/rio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rodaguayo.github.io/project/rio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assessing the glacier projection uncertainties in the Southern Andes (40-56°S) from a catchment perspective&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;screen reader text&#34; title=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RIO (river in English) project seeks to improve understanding of the environment and encourage reasoned decision-making with critical and reflective thinking. Chilean society, although it values rivers and coastal systems, still has a strong lack of knowledge about the virtuous connections that are generated between them. Follow us in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/documental.rio/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; (spanish content).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trailer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jglNxijOhj0&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full documentary&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/afFa82quvK0&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
